Taylor Laekeman

github.com/tjlaekem · tjlaekem.dev hello@tjlaekem.dev

Skills

Full-stack developer with frontend and backend experience building web applications and data science tools. I've worked on cross-functional teams and mentored interns, junior teammates, and new hires.

Experience with HTML/CSS/JavaScript, React, Redux, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, and Kafka.

Experience

Canvass Analytics Full Stack Software Engineer

August 2018-Present

React, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Kafka

- Canvass offers a platform that allows industrial engineers to train models and gain insight on their processes through data science
- · Designed, developed, and iterated a data ingestion pipeline built with Kafka
- · Used Kubeflow to build a pipeline to facilitate and orchestrate model training and deployment
- · Built a redesigned web client from scratch with React
- · Mentored the team's development interns
- · Participated in the recruitment process as the development team grew from two to ten people

Waterloo Co-op Internships Various Roles

January 2013-December 2017

C#, React, Python, Java, Android

- Twenty-eight months combined work experience with Fourwalls Digital, AbacusNext, Encircle, Metricwire, CBTS Canada, Cyclica, and Agriculture and Agri-Food Canada
- · Learned the basics of agile development, and how teams work together to complete large technical projects
- · Learned to communicate effectively and professionally with other developers and stakeholders
- · Learned how to quickly familiarize myself with new technologies and existing code

Projects

Ciao, Estrela Co. Principal Engineer

January 2018-Present

React, Python, Django, PostgreSQL

- · Ciao, Estrela is my partner's art business, through which she sells custom cards and commissions
- Built and deployed a RESTful API server using Python, Django, and PostgreSQL, an e-commerce website using React, and an admin portal that allows my partner to manage listings on the shop
- · The customer-facing site is available at ciaoestrela.co

Education

University of Waterloo

Graduated June 2018

Bachelor of Applied Science in Honours Computer Engineering, Co-operative Program